Matthew Bogard

(512) 961-9526

mbogard.com

↑ 1200 Barton Hills Drive, Austin, TX 78704



Proficient Technologies

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

jQuery

MySQL

MongoDB

Express.js

React.js

Node.js

Swift

SUMMARY

Creative and quick-learning software developer fluent in all levels of the MERN tech stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js). As a full-stack developer, I feel comfortable creating modern front-end designs as well as manipulating databases through server requests. I can confidently jump into a complicated existing code base and resolve issues alone, but I also enjoy working with a team of developers for larger projects. Embraces opportunities to expand technical expertise.

FEATURED WORK

US Census Data Visualization, Full-Stack Web Application

 Allows users to more easily navigate and analyze American city data. Specifically, the app leverages Chart.js for graphics, Sequelize for object-relational mapping, and ES6 JavaScript features for test-driven development. us-census-data.herokuapp.com

Compass, Full-Stack Web Application

 Empowers users with new tools for searching for film/television content. This web application uses some ES6 JavaScript features such as async/await functions when requesting data from the Gracenote API.
mbogard.com/Compass

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NPR/WSJ News Scraper, MongoDB and React.js Application

• Users can search for news articles as well as save and comment on articles.

Deep Dream, iOS Application

 An interactive story application written in Swift. To be released in the iOS app store in 2019.

Texas Health and Human Services, Front-End Mobile Compatibility

• Provided fixes for bugs in the mobile display of the organization's homepage.

SKILLS

- Adept manager of developer repos with Git version control and SourceTree
- o Expertise in advanced deployment technologies such as Heroku & JawsDB
- O Highly skilled at writing clean and readable code that explains its structure/logic

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin, May 2018–Present

The Coding Boot Camp Program Certificate Program

The University of Texas at Austin, 2013-2016

Graduate - Bachelor of Arts in Government, Minor in Rhetoric and Writing Cumulative GPA: 3.5

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Texas Health and Human Services, Rate Analysis Department

- Project Manager (Promotion)January–June 2018
- o Rate Analyst January 2017–January 2018

The Brookings Institution, Research Intern in Governance Studies

Spring 2015 (Washington, D.C.)

Plus three other internships while attending university

Lieutenant Governor Political Campaign, Spectrum News' *Capital Tonight*, & Project Vote Smart Summer 2013 — Summer 2014 (Austin, TX)